const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Chewing of tobacco leads to oral cancer mostly in:","answers":[{"option":"North America","bool":false},{"option":"China","bool":false},{"option":"India","bool":true},{"option":"South America","bool":false},{"option":"Bangladesh","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Anterior fontanelle closes at what age?","answers":[{"option":"4 to 5 months","bool":false},{"option":"1 to 2 months","bool":false},{"option":"After 2 years","bool":false},{"option":"6 to 7 years","bool":false},{"option":"9 to 18 months","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"A clinician examines the extrinsic musculature of the eyes of a 50-year-old female patient. All extraocular muscles are functioning fine except one. Which of the following muscles is affected based on the action mentioned?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior rectus-looks downwards","bool":false},{"option":"Superior oblique-looks medially and upwards","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral rectus-looks laterally","bool":false},{"option":"Superior rectus-looks medially and upwards","bool":false},{"option":"Medial rectus- looks medially","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is a feature of complete anterior cleft anomaly?","answers":[{"option":"Cleft extends through lips and alveolar part of maxilla to the incisive fossa on both sides","bool":false},{"option":"Cleft extends through lips and alveolar part of maxilla","bool":false},{"option":"Cleft extends through maxilla and hard palate","bool":false},{"option":"Cleft extends through lip, maxilla, soft palate, and hard palate","bool":false},{"option":"Cleft extends through upper lip and alveolar part of maxilla to the incisive fossa","bool":true}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"A surgeon, while performing surgery for removal of lymph nodes from the posterior triangle of the neck, is liable to damage which one of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Supraclavicular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Greater auricular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser occipital nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding the features of the pigmented epithelium layer of the retina?","answers":[{"option":"It consists of simple columnar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"It contains stores of vitamin A","bool":false},{"option":"It consists of stratified columnar epithelium","bool":true},{"option":"The cells show phagocytic activity","bool":false},{"option":"It strongly adheres to Bruch's membrane of choroid","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a feature of a typical cervical vertebra?","answers":[{"option":"Triangular vertebral foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Dens","bool":true},{"option":"Bifid spinous process","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Body","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which bone has a major contribution to the formation of the nasal septum?","answers":[{"option":"Rostrum of sphenoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary palatine crest","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal spine of frontal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Perpendicular plate of ethmoid bone","bool":true},{"option":"Perpendicular plate of palatine bone","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"What is the most common location for a thyroglossal duct cyst?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior to hyoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"At the base of tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Superior to hyoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior to hyoid bone","bool":true},{"option":"Superior mediastinum","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"A lesion of the optic chiasma causes which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of vision in the right eye","bool":false},{"option":"Heteronymous bitemporal hemianopsia","bool":true},{"option":"Homonymous hemianopsia","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of vision in the left eye","bool":false},{"option":"Homonymous contralateral hemianopsia","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following muscles contributes to palatine aponeurosis?","answers":[{"option":"Palatopharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Tensor veli palatini","bool":true},{"option":"Palatoglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Genioglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Stylopharyngeus","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a characteristic feature of circumvallate papillae?","answers":[{"option":"Mucous secretions are in the grooves around them","bool":true},{"option":"They are supplied by the glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"They are 8-12 in number","bool":false},{"option":"They are largest papillae","bool":false},{"option":"They are surrounded by grooves","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Bell palsy involves the lesion of which nerve?","answers":[{"option":"7th","bool":true},{"option":"6th","bool":false},{"option":"5th","bool":false},{"option":"12th","bool":false},{"option":"3rd","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The auditory ossicles articulate through which kind of joint?","answers":[{"option":"Fibrocartilaginous joint","bool":false},{"option":"Cartilaginous joint","bool":false},{"option":"Syndesmoses","bool":false},{"option":"Synovial joint","bool":true},{"option":"Fibrous joint","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following branches of the maxillary artery passes through the foramen spinosum?","answers":[{"option":"Accessory meningeal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Nasopalatine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenopalatine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Greater palatine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle meningeal artery","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which branch of the cervical plexus does not supply skin?","answers":[{"option":"Transverse cervical nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Supraclavicular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Branches from C1","bool":true},{"option":"Lesser occipital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Greater auricular nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"A student is concerned about a muscle in the neck which is related to the borders of both anterior and posterior triangles. Which muscle is this?","answers":[{"option":"Trapezius","bool":false},{"option":"Omohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Digastric","bool":false},{"option":"Rectus capitis","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"A young patient presents to the outpatient department with an ulcer on the tongue. Which of the following lymph nodes will most likely be enlarged?","answers":[{"option":"Deep cervical","bool":false},{"option":"Jugulo-omyhoid","bool":true},{"option":"Jugulodigastric","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid","bool":false},{"option":"Supraclavicular","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Where is the primary auditory cortex located?","answers":[{"option":"Occipital lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal lobe","bool":true},{"option":"Parietal lobe","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Deflection of the stereocilia away from the kinocilium in the cochlea causes which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Closing of potassium channels","bool":true},{"option":"Opening of sodium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Closing of sodium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Closing of sodium-chloride channels","bool":false},{"option":"Opening of chloride channels","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"A patient presents with his right eye deviated down and out. On examination, there is a double vision on moving the eye to the right. Which nerve is damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Right trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Right oculomotor nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Left trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Left oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Right ophthalmic nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The vestibular nucleus helps maintain body balance through connections with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":true},{"option":"Occipital lobe","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The intrinsic muscles of the larynx are derivatives of which pharyngeal arch?","answers":[{"option":"6th","bool":true},{"option":"4th","bool":false},{"option":"1st","bool":false},{"option":"3rd","bool":false},{"option":"2nd","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Boundaries of the pyriform aperture are formed by which of the following bones?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary and zygomatic","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal and maxillary","bool":true},{"option":"Frontal and maxillary","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal and frontal","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary and sphenoid","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a branch of the facial artery?","answers":[{"option":"Superior labial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal nasal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior labial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral nasal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Submental artery","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The transverse facial artery is a branch of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital artery","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial temporal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior auricular artery","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The lateral rectus muscle is supplied by which nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Oculomotor","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear","bool":false},{"option":"Facial","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The carotid sinus is innervated by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which one of the following is not a tributary of the external jugular vein?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior branch of retromandibular vein","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior auricular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Suprascapular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior branch of retromandibular vein","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Extraocular muscles of the eye are chiefly supplied by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The rods and cones of the retina are part of which layer?","answers":[{"option":"Inner limiting membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Inner nuclear layer","bool":false},{"option":"Outer plexiform layer","bool":false},{"option":"Outer nuclear layer","bool":true},{"option":"Inner plexiform layer","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The rhombencephalic isthmus separates which parts of the brain?","answers":[{"option":"Myelencephalon from the spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Mesencephalon from the metencephalon","bool":true},{"option":"Metencephalon from the myelencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Prosencephalon from the diencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Rhombencephalon from the mesencephalon","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"While turning the head from side to side, like when saying \"no\", the main movement occurs at which joint?","answers":[{"option":"C7-T1","bool":false},{"option":"Atlanto-occipital joint","bool":false},{"option":"C1-C2","bool":false},{"option":"Atlanto-axial joint","bool":true},{"option":"C2-C3","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which facial nerve branches are present in the middle ear?","answers":[{"option":"Deep petrosal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Greater petrosal nerve and nerve to stapedius","bool":false},{"option":"Chorda tympani and greater petrosal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Chorda tympani and nerve to stapedius","bool":true},{"option":"Vidian nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a branch of the external carotid artery?","answers":[{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenopalatine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Supraorbital artery","bool":true},{"option":"Occipital artery","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary artery","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following nerves supplies the skin over the angle of the mandible?","answers":[{"option":"Greater auricular nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Lesser auricular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Long thoracic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior auricular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"What is the normal intraocular pressure (IOP) range?","answers":[{"option":"10-60 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"12-20 mmHg","bool":true},{"option":"5-10 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"0-5 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"10-30 mmHg","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding the composition of saliva?","answers":[{"option":"Contains proteins","bool":false},{"option":"IgA antibodies secretion","bool":false},{"option":"Isotonic to plasma","bool":true},{"option":"Mostly contains water","bool":false},{"option":"Contains mucin","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"A young man had a car accident and came to the emergency room (ER) with a fracture of a facial bone that is unpaired. Which bone is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Nasal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary bone","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomatic bone","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Mandible bone","bool":true}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"A patient presented with a fracture of the middle third of the clavicle. What is the appropriate boundary of the posterior triangle formed by the fractured structure?","answers":[{"option":"Floor","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Apex","bool":false},{"option":"Base","bool":true}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Presence of which of the following in food results in a bitter taste?","answers":[{"option":"Aldehydes","bool":false},{"option":"Alkaloids","bool":true},{"option":"HCO3-","bool":false},{"option":"Ketones","bool":false},{"option":"H+","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which veins connect the veins of the scalp to the dural venous sinuses?","answers":[{"option":"Subarachnoid veins","bool":false},{"option":"Diploic veins","bool":false},{"option":"Auricular veins","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral veins","bool":false},{"option":"Emissary veins","bool":true}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is not true regarding the blood supply of the face?","answers":[{"option":"External carotid artery supplies the face","bool":false},{"option":"Facial artery supplies the lacrimal sac","bool":false},{"option":"Terminal branch of facial artery anastomoses with dorsal nasal branch","bool":false},{"option":"Facial artery enters by crossing the neck of mandible","bool":true},{"option":"Supratrochlear and supraorbital arteries supply the forehead","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The sour taste of food is due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"HCO3- ions","bool":false},{"option":"Ketones","bool":false},{"option":"Alkaloids","bool":false},{"option":"H+ ions","bool":true},{"option":"Aldehydes","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which nerve supplies the general sensation for the anterior 2/3rd of the tongue?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual","bool":true},{"option":"Facial","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which muscle is enclosed by the investing layer of the deep cervical fascia of the neck?","answers":[{"option":"Geniohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Digastric","bool":false},{"option":"Mylohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid","bool":true},{"option":"Omohyoid","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following does not pass through the internal auditory meatus?","answers":[{"option":"Labyrinthine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Cochlear part of vestibulocochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibular part of vestibulocochlear nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The speech and tone are produced with the assistance of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Tongue","bool":true},{"option":"Pharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Larynx","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following communicates with the middle cranial fossa, oral cavity, nasal cavity, and orbital cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Infratemporal fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen spinosum","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen lacerum","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygopalatine fossa","bool":true}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The pterygoid venous plexus drains into which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"External jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Cavernous sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle meningeal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Facial vein","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary vein","bool":true}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is true regarding the structure of taste buds?","answers":[{"option":"They are mainly located on the soft palate but few on the ventral surface of tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Apex of the taste buds communicate with the oral cavity through taste pore","bool":true},{"option":"Sustentacular cells of taste buds are also known as gustatory cells","bool":false},{"option":"Taste buds are embedded within epithelium covering the  filiform papillae","bool":false},{"option":"A taste bud consists of 10-12 cells","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"What is the first step in the resynthesis of rhodopsin?","answers":[{"option":"All cis retinol conversion to 11-trans retinol","bool":false},{"option":"All trans retinal conversion to 10-cis retinal","bool":false},{"option":"All trans retinol conversion to 11-cis retinol","bool":false},{"option":"All cis retinal conversion to 11-trans retinal","bool":false},{"option":"All trans retinal conversion to 11-cis retinal","bool":true}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"What does ageusia refer to?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of hearing","bool":false},{"option":"Partial loss of smell","bool":false},{"option":"Partial loss of taste","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of smell","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of taste","bool":true}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Sensory innervation of laryngopharynx is by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Pharyngeal branch of maxillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"External laryngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Internal branch of superior laryngeal nerve","bool":true}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Retinol falls under which of the following functional groups?","answers":[{"option":"Ethers","bool":false},{"option":"Esters","bool":false},{"option":"Ketones","bool":false},{"option":"Alcohols","bool":true},{"option":"Aldehydes","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following nerve fibers form the inferior root of ansa cervicalis?","answers":[{"option":"C3 and C5","bool":false},{"option":"C1 and C3","bool":false},{"option":"C3 and C4","bool":false},{"option":"C1 and C2","bool":false},{"option":"C2 and C3","bool":true}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"A boy came to the outpatient department with a swelling below and at the back of the angle of the mandible. He was diagnosed with a jugulodigastric node blockage. What will be the site of pathology?","answers":[{"option":"Pharyngeal tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid gland","bool":false},{"option":"Palatine tonsils","bool":true},{"option":"Tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Pharynx","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The cerebellum is derivative of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Telencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Metencephalon","bool":true},{"option":"Diencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Myelencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Rhombencephalon","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Where is the structure posterior to the pupil derived from?","answers":[{"option":"Surface ectoderm","bool":true},{"option":"Paraxial ectoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral ectoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Neuroectoderm","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is incorrect about salivary glands?","answers":[{"option":"Serous cell are predominant cells of submandibular gland","bool":false},{"option":"Intercalated ducts are wider and longer in the parotid gland","bool":false},{"option":"All minor salivary glands are serous in nature","bool":true},{"option":"All minor salivary gland are not encapsulated","bool":false},{"option":"Demilune cells secrete lysozyme in sublingual gland","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Von Ebner's gland is what type of gland?","answers":[{"option":"Seromucous","bool":false},{"option":"Sebaceous glands","bool":false},{"option":"Mucous","bool":false},{"option":"Sweat glands","bool":false},{"option":"Serous","bool":true}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which nerve supplies muscles of facial expression?","answers":[{"option":"Mandibular","bool":false},{"option":"Facial","bool":true},{"option":"Hypoglossal","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The auditory ossicle(s) attached to the oval window is/are derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"4th pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"3rd pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular arch","bool":false},{"option":"Hyoid arch","bool":true},{"option":"1st pharyngeal arch","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Where are the infrahyoid muscles present?","answers":[{"option":"Submental triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Muscular triangle","bool":true},{"option":"Carotid triangle","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Sensory retina develops from which part of the optic cup?","answers":[{"option":"Outer layer of the optic cup","bool":false},{"option":"Pars ciliaris retinae","bool":false},{"option":"Pars optica retinae","bool":true},{"option":"Pars iridica retinae","bool":false},{"option":"Pars caeca retinae","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"11-cis-retinal is derived from which vitamin?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin A","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin K","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin C","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B12","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B9","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"What is the composition of rhodopsin?","answers":[{"option":"opsin + 11-cis-retinal","bool":false},{"option":"scotopsin + 11-trans-retinal","bool":false},{"option":"iodopsin + 11-trans-retinal","bool":false},{"option":"scotopsin + 11-cis-retinal","bool":true},{"option":"iodopsin + 11-cis-retinal","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"What equalizes pressure in the middle ear cavity and pharynx?","answers":[{"option":"Oval window","bool":false},{"option":"Eustachian tube","bool":true},{"option":"Tympanic membrane","bool":false},{"option":"External acoustic meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Auditory ossicles","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a branch of the ophthalmic artery?","answers":[{"option":"Zygomaticofacial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Supratrochlear artery","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomaticotemporal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Infraorbital artery","bool":true},{"option":"Supraorbital artery","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"What forms the lower and posterior part of the nasal septum?","answers":[{"option":"Palatine process of maxilla","bool":false},{"option":"Vomer","bool":true},{"option":"Vertical plate of ethmoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Perpendicular plate of palatine bone","bool":false},{"option":"Body of sphenoid","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The parafollicular cells (C-cells) of the thyroid are derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Ultimobranchial body","bool":true},{"option":"First pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"Third pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"Second pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"Second pharyngeal cleft","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Sialadenitis mostly involves the parotid gland and is caused by non-specific bacterial infection. When it involves the submandibular gland, what is the infection secondary to?","answers":[{"option":"Stone","bool":true},{"option":"Infection by staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Infection by mumps virus","bool":false},{"option":"Sjogren syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammation","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"What forms from the pars optica retinae?","answers":[{"option":"Ciliary body","bool":false},{"option":"Dilator pupillae muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Inner layer of the iris","bool":false},{"option":"Pigmented layer of retina","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory part of retina","bool":true}]},{"id":73,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is true regarding most minor salivary glands?","answers":[{"option":"They have numerous excretory units","bool":false},{"option":"They are seromucous","bool":false},{"option":"They are serous","bool":false},{"option":"They are mucous","bool":true},{"option":"They are encapsulated","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"What synapses with rods and cones in the outer plexiform layer?","answers":[{"option":"Horizontal and bipolar cells","bool":true},{"option":"Bipolar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Amacrine and bipolar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Amacrine cells","bool":false},{"option":"Ganglion cells","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which is the derivative of the second pharyngeal pouch?","answers":[{"option":"Lingual tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Palatine tonsils","bool":true},{"option":"Superior parathyroid glands","bool":false},{"option":"Pharyngeal tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior parathyroid glands","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of these is not formed from the dorsal part of the otic vesicle?","answers":[{"option":"Endolymphatic duct","bool":false},{"option":"Semilunar ducts","bool":false},{"option":"Saccule","bool":true},{"option":"Utricle","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous labyrinth","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which nucleus in the brainstem receives fibers carrying taste sensations?","answers":[{"option":"Nucleus of tractus solitarius","bool":true},{"option":"Nucleus of pneumotaxic centre","bool":false},{"option":"Vasomotor centre","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus ambiguus","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal nuclei","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which is true regarding the venous drainage of face?","answers":[{"option":"Facial vein drains into external jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Facial vein communicates with inferior ophthalmic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Facial vein communicates with cavernous sinus through angular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Facial vein has unidirectional valves","bool":false},{"option":"Deep facial vein drains into the pterygoid plexus","bool":true}]},{"id":79,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The axons of ganglionic cells transmitting action potential synapse in the midbrain with which of the following structure?","answers":[{"option":"Superior colliculus","bool":true},{"option":"Medial geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Optic radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior colliculus","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Correction of cleft lip usually occurs during which month?","answers":[{"option":"3rd month","bool":true},{"option":"6th month","bool":false},{"option":"10th month","bool":false},{"option":"12th month","bool":false},{"option":"9th month","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which is not present in the carotid sheath?","answers":[{"option":"Internal carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Internal jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Common carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"External jugular vein","bool":true},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Squamous papilloma is caused by which of these?","answers":[{"option":"HPV (human papilloma virus) 16 & 18","bool":false},{"option":"Coronavirus","bool":false},{"option":"EBV (Epstein-Barr virus)","bool":false},{"option":"HPV (human papilloma virus) 6 & 11","bool":true},{"option":"Adenovirus","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The nasolacrimal duct opens into which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Superior meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Hiatus semilunaris","bool":false},{"option":"Infundibulum","bool":false},{"option":"Spheno-ethmoidal recess","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior meatus","bool":true}]},{"id":84,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following muscles is not supplied by the mandibular nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Buccinator","bool":true},{"option":"Temporalis","bool":false},{"option":"Masseter","bool":false},{"option":"Medial pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which is the recent technique to correct myopia?","answers":[{"option":"Laser epithelial keratomileusis (LASEK)","bool":false},{"option":"Photorefractive keratectomy (PRK)","bool":false},{"option":"Radial keratotomy (RK)","bool":false},{"option":"Laser-assisted in situ keratomileusis (LASIK)","bool":true},{"option":"Conductive keratoplasty (CK)","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is the relation of the facial nerve with the parotid gland?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial to artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial to gland","bool":false},{"option":"Deep to gland","bool":false},{"option":"Deep to arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial to vein","bool":true}]},{"id":87,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following forms the anterior boundary of the temporal fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Temporal lines and zygomatic process of zygomatic bone","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior aspect of maxilla and frontal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomatic arch and zygomatic process of frontal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid plate and frontal process of frontal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal process of zygomatic bone and zygomatic process of frontal bone","bool":true}]},{"id":88,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which molecules help in the depolarization of the olfactory membrane when odorant molecules combine with it?","answers":[{"option":"K+ ions","bool":false},{"option":"Ca+2 ions","bool":false},{"option":"Mg+2 ions","bool":false},{"option":"Cl- ions","bool":false},{"option":"Na+ ions","bool":true}]},{"id":89,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The triangular primary palate is formed by the fusion of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Medial nasal prominence","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary prominence with lateral nasal prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Two lateral nasal prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Two mandibular prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Two maxillary prominence","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"What is found in the pterygopalatine fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Infraorbital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"External carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Third part of maxillary artery","bool":true}]},{"id":91,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Visual fibers also pass through the pretectal nucleus in the midbrain. Pretectal nucleus is associated with which of the following function?","answers":[{"option":"Accommodation reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Balance and equilibrium","bool":false},{"option":"Pupillary light reflex","bool":true},{"option":"Attenuation reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Color sensation","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"To maintain equilibrium, the vestibular nerve passes from the vestibular apparatus to which of these?","answers":[{"option":"Nucleus ambiguus","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibular nucleus and cerebellum","bool":true},{"option":"Tractus solitarius","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus gracilis","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal nucleus of trigeminal","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The auriculotemporal nerve is a branch of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Greater occipital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Ophthalmic nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"What is the term used for the dryness of the oral cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Steatorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Sialithiosis","bool":false},{"option":"Xerostomia","bool":true},{"option":"Keratosis","bool":false},{"option":"Sialorrhea","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following nerves in the oral mucosa is in danger when the molar teeth and gingivae are being operated on?","answers":[{"option":"Lingual nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Mental nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior alveolar nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Nerve to lateral pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Buccal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"During infection of the parotid gland (parotitis), pain occurs due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Nerve compression","bool":false},{"option":"Swelling of the gland","bool":false},{"option":"Gland enlargement","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid sheath limits swelling","bool":true},{"option":"Chewing","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which nonionizing modality can be used to visualize the thyroid at bedside?","answers":[{"option":"X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"CT","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray rotating envelope","bool":false},{"option":"MRI","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":true}]},{"id":98,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding the lacrimal apparatus?","answers":[{"option":"Tears flow to the lacrimal puncta","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal glands drain into superficial parotid lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal glands are of simple tubuloacinar type","bool":true},{"option":"Tears collect in the conjunctival fornix","bool":false},{"option":"Secretions produced are called tears","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding Von Ebner glands?","answers":[{"option":"Found on anterior 2/3rd of tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Produce serous secretions","bool":true},{"option":"Present beneath filiform papillae","bool":false},{"option":"Simple tubular glands","bool":false},{"option":"Produce mucous secretion","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"A person injures his mandible (ramus) in an accident. Which boundary of the wall of the infratemporal fossa does it form?","answers":[{"option":"Medial wall","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior wall","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior wall","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior wall","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral wall","bool":true}]},{"id":101,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Where is the keratin layer present in the oral cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Lips","bool":false},{"option":"Soft palate","bool":false},{"option":"Hard palate","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar mucosa","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding eyelids?","answers":[{"option":"Contain modified sweat glands called meibomian glands","bool":true},{"option":"Tarsal plates are covered by skin","bool":false},{"option":"Contain sweat glands of moll","bool":false},{"option":"Covered by layer of elastic skin","bool":false},{"option":"Lined internally by palpebral conjunctiva","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which muscle is involved in forcefully closing eyelids?","answers":[{"option":"Orbital part of orbicularis occuli","bool":true},{"option":"Palpebral part of orbicularis occuli","bool":false},{"option":"Levator palpebrae superioris","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal part of orbicularis occuli","bool":false},{"option":"Procerus","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"What is the most common malignant carcinoma of salivary glands?","answers":[{"option":"Warthin tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Ooncocystoma","bool":false},{"option":"Adenoid cystic carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Pleomorphic adenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Mucoepidermoid carcinoma","bool":true}]},{"id":105,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Nasopharyngeal carcinomas are mostly associated with which virus?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatitis B virus (HBV)","bool":false},{"option":"Epstein Barr virus (EBV)","bool":true},{"option":"Cytomegalovirus (CMV)","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis C virus (HCV)","bool":false},{"option":"Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which structures are paired correctly?","answers":[{"option":"Sphenoid process of maxilla","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygoid plate of the parietal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Styloid process of temporal bone","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior nasal spine of maxilla","bool":false},{"option":"Greater wing of frontal bone","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"A young girl presents to the clinic with an infection of the auricular lobule due to wearing earrings. The infection drains to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Deep cervical nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Mastoid nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial cervical nodes","bool":true}]},{"id":108,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Aphakia is associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hyphema","bool":false},{"option":"Astigmatism","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudoaphakia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypermetropia","bool":true},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following statements is correct?","answers":[{"option":"When the lens is at rest, the ciliaris muscle is contracted","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperopia can be corrected by a diverging lens","bool":false},{"option":"Emmetropia is a condition with errors in refraction","bool":false},{"option":"Lens is the major refractive component of the eye","bool":false},{"option":"Myopia can be corrected by a diverging lens","bool":true}]},{"id":110,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"A patient presents with raised intraocular pressure, redness of the eye, shallow anterior chamber, headache, nausea, and vomiting. Which of the following conditions is indicated?","answers":[{"option":"Open-angle glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Hyphema","bool":false},{"option":"Cataracts","bool":false},{"option":"Uveitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute close-angle glaucoma","bool":true}]},{"id":111,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Excitation of photoreceptors by light leads to which changes in rhodopsin?","answers":[{"option":"Lumirhodopsin to metarhodopsin","bool":true},{"option":"Bathorhodopsin to rhodopsin","bool":false},{"option":"Metrhodopsin to bathorodopsin","bool":false},{"option":"Lumirhodopsin to bathorhodopsin","bool":false},{"option":"All-trans retinol to all-trans retinal","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"In lateral view of an X-ray of the head, a physician notices the meeting point of parietooccipital, occipitomastoid, and lambdoid sutures. What is this point called?","answers":[{"option":"Bregma","bool":false},{"option":"Asterion","bool":true},{"option":"Inion","bool":false},{"option":"Pterion","bool":false},{"option":"Lambda","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The auditory ossicles which are attached to the oval window are derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"4nd pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"1st pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"3rd pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"2nd pharyngeal arch","bool":true}]},{"id":114,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Lips and palate form during which time period?","answers":[{"option":"7-8 months","bool":false},{"option":"4-5 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"5-6 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"7-8 weeks","bool":true},{"option":"4-5 months","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of these are included in the complete cleft anomaly?","answers":[{"option":"Alveolar process of maxilla + incisive fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Lip + alveolar process of maxilla + incisive fossa","bool":true},{"option":"Lip + alveolar process of maxilla","bool":false},{"option":"Lip + alveolar process of maxilla + incisive fossa on both sides","bool":false},{"option":"Lip + incisive fossa","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding temporomandibular joint (TMJ)?","answers":[{"option":"All muscles are supplied by the mandibular branch of trigeminal nerve except the medial pterygoid","bool":true},{"option":"Temporalis is the primary retractor","bool":false},{"option":"All of these are correct","bool":false},{"option":"Muscles related to it are derived from 1st pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"All muscles acting at temporomandibular joint (TMJ) elevate the jaw except lateral pterygoid","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following occurs as a result of the blockage of the drainage of the aqueous humor?","answers":[{"option":"Coloboma","bool":false},{"option":"Amblyopia","bool":false},{"option":"Strabismus","bool":false},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":true},{"option":"Cataract","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which type of cells are olfactory receptor cells?","answers":[{"option":"Bipolar neuron","bool":true},{"option":"Unipolar neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudounipolar neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Multipolar neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Nonneuronal","bool":false}]},{"id":119,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which is not true about the retina?","answers":[{"option":"It is the photoreceptor layer","bool":false},{"option":"Two retinal layers can easily be detached","bool":false},{"option":"It is highly vascular","bool":false},{"option":"It terminates at ora serrata","bool":false},{"option":"The innermost layer of the retina contains the rods and cones","bool":true}]},{"id":120,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which technique is advised to see the extent of a mass lesion of orbit?","answers":[{"option":"MRI","bool":false},{"option":"CT scan","bool":true},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"PET scan","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral view of skull via X-ray","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Along with the hypoglossal nerve, what else forms the floor of the submandibular (digastric) triangle?","answers":[{"option":"Omohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Sternothyroid","bool":false},{"option":"Sternohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Thyrohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Mylohyoid","bool":true}]},{"id":122,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The external jugular vein is formed by the union of which of the following veins?","answers":[{"option":"Transverse sinus and anterior division of retromandibular","bool":false},{"option":"Sigmoid sinus and posterior division of retromandibular","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior division of retromandibular and posterior auricular","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary and posterior auricular","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygoid and posterior auricular","bool":false}]},{"id":123,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which is true regarding the composition of endolymph?","answers":[{"option":"Same as extracellular fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Has a potassium concentration close to extracellular fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Same as intracellular fluid","bool":true},{"option":"Same as interstitial fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Has a sodium concentration close to extracellular fluid","bool":false}]},{"id":124,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which type of lens is a concave lens?","answers":[{"option":"Reflecting","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Diverging","bool":true},{"option":"Magnifying","bool":false},{"option":"Converging","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following muscles is not derived from the 2nd pharyngeal arch?","answers":[{"option":"Levator veli palatini","bool":true},{"option":"Buccinator","bool":false},{"option":"Stapedius","bool":false},{"option":"Stylohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior belly of digastric","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding the tongue surface?","answers":[{"option":"Covered by stratified squamous epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Contains elevations called papilla","bool":false},{"option":"Contains minor salivary glands that secrete seromucous secretions","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual papillae are formed by stratified squamous epithelium only","bool":false},{"option":"Covered by stratified columnar epithelium","bool":true}]},{"id":127,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"All trans-retinoic acid and 9-cis-retinoic acids are responsible for which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Growth hormones","bool":false},{"option":"Iron metabolism","bool":false},{"option":"Cholesterol synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Growth and cellular differentiation","bool":true},{"option":"Bone development","bool":false}]},{"id":128,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding bitot spots?","answers":[{"option":"Seen in neovascularization","bool":false},{"option":"Localized increase in thickness of cornea","bool":true},{"option":"Clouding of cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Blood in cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Seen in glaucoma","bool":false}]},{"id":129,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The odorant molecule receptors are activated by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Alpha subunit","bool":false},{"option":"Ion channels","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine complex","bool":false},{"option":"G protein system","bool":true},{"option":"Beta subunit","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"In which layer of the scalp does an infection spread easily?","answers":[{"option":"Aponeurosis","bool":false},{"option":"Periosteum","bool":false},{"option":"Skin","bool":false},{"option":"Loose connective tissue","bool":true},{"option":"Connective tissue","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding the choroid layer of the eyeball?","answers":[{"option":"It is tightly attached to the sclera","bool":false},{"option":"It has a rich nerve supply","bool":false},{"option":"It is completely avascular","bool":false},{"option":"It is located in the anterior 1/3rd of the eye","bool":false},{"option":"Its cells contain melanin pigment","bool":true}]},{"id":132,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding the ciliary ganglion?","answers":[{"option":"Preganglionic sympathetic fibers synapse here","bool":false},{"option":"Postganglionic parasympathetic fibers reach eye via the short ciliary nerves","bool":true},{"option":"Postganglionic sympathetic fibers only reach the eye via short ciliary nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Postganglionic parasympathetic fibers reach the eye via long ciliary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"It is located outside the muscle cone","bool":false}]},{"id":133,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding the parotid gland?","answers":[{"option":"Retromandibular vein is formed superficial to the gland","bool":false},{"option":"Its duct opens in the oral cavity opposite the second molar tooth","bool":true},{"option":"Facial nerve crosses superficial to it","bool":false},{"option":"Its duct pierces the masseter muscle on the way to oral cavity","bool":false},{"option":"It is the second largest salivary gland","bool":false}]},{"id":134,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"What is true regarding the pharyngeal and esophageal phases of swallowing?","answers":[{"option":"Voluntary and involuntary","bool":false},{"option":"Voluntary only","bool":false},{"option":"Respiration is inhibited","bool":false},{"option":"The esophageal phase is faster than the pharyngeal phase","bool":false},{"option":"Involuntary only","bool":true}]},{"id":135,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"A patient presents with a lesion of an optic tract. As a result, he is unable to see on the opposite side of the head from both eyes. This condition is called?","answers":[{"option":"Unilateral hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Unihedral hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Trihedral hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Homonymous hemianopia","bool":true},{"option":"Bitemporal hemianopia","bool":false}]},{"id":136,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"In a lesion at the superior orbital fissure, which structure will not be involved?","answers":[{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Ophthalmic veins","bool":false}]},{"id":137,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"A boy presents with difficulty in breathing and pain in the throat. Which of the following would be swollen?","answers":[{"option":"Lingual tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Palatine tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Pharyngeal tonsils","bool":true},{"option":"Supraclavicular tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical lymph nodes","bool":false}]},{"id":138,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is affected when the left side of vision of both the eyes is affected?","answers":[{"option":"Right optic tract","bool":true},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Both optic tracts","bool":false},{"option":"Right cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":false}]},{"id":139,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following is the common fibrous proliferative lesion of the oral cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Erythroplakia","bool":false},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Leukoplakia","bool":false},{"option":"Pyogenic granuloma","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroma","bool":true}]},{"id":140,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Axons of which cells form the optic nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Bipolar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Rod cells","bool":false},{"option":"Horizontal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Amacrine cells","bool":false},{"option":"Ganglion cells","bool":true}]},{"id":141,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"The deficiency of vitamin A causes a pathological condition called xerophthalmia. Which of the following correctly describes it?","answers":[{"option":"Poor vision at night","bool":false},{"option":"Dryness of cornea along with cloudy appearance","bool":false},{"option":"Thickening of a part of cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Dryness of the cornea and conjuctiva","bool":true},{"option":"Poor vision in dim light","bool":false}]},{"id":142,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","question":"Which of the following are the eye muscles derived from?","answers":[{"option":"Trilaminar disc","bool":false},{"option":"Epimere","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital somites","bool":false},{"option":"Hypomere","bool":false},{"option":"Preotic somites","bool":true}]}]
export default arr